### Contact

mdharris206@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michael-d-harris (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Project Management
Business Process Improvement
Cross-functional Team Leadership

### Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Six Sigma Green Belt Certification

# Michael D. Harris

Industrial Engineer II at Hoshizaki America

Greater Atlanta Area

## Summary

Adaptable, forward-thinking Industrial Process Engineer with expertise applying fundamental concepts, practices, and procedures to analyze operational data, identify performance improvement opportunities within transportation, industrial, retail, and medical industries. Progressive background in product development, project management, client relations, and multi-site operations. Lifelong learner keeping pace with industry and technology advancements. Operates well in fast-paced settings, managing multiple tasks, and changing priorities.

Technical Skills: Python, Java, R, ProEngineer, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, C++, CMM, MiniTab, SQL, Excel, Windchill, PTC Creo

#### KEY SKILLS AND CORE COMPETENCIES

- Team Leadership
- ► Process Analysis / Redesign
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- ► Business Needs Assessment
- Analytical Problem Solving
- ► Multi-Site Operations
- ► Project Lifecycle Management
- Quantitative Data Management
- Cost Analysis
- ► Research / Data analysis
- Developing Standard Operating Procedures
- ► Supply Chain Logistics
- Six Sigma / Lean Methodologies
- Solution Implementation
- ► Presentation Skills

# Experience

Georgia Tech Professional Education Georgia Tech Coding Boot Camp April 2019 - Present

Atlanta, Georgia

Full Stack Flex course to gain the knowledge and skills for building dynamic end-to-end web applications as a full stack web developer. A rigorous and fast-paced immersion into theory and web development application. Collaborating with area employers on real world projects.

Topics included:

HTML5, CSS, Responsive Design, Boostrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, Cookies, Local Storage, React.js, Heroku, Git, Git Hub, ASP.Net, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Security and Session Storage, User Authentication, MERN Stack, Writing Tests, Data Structures, Algorithms

Hoshizaki America Industrial Engineer II November 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Greater Atlanta Area

Partner with clients to define, plan, and maintain efficient production labor standards for fabrication facility that manufactures parts and finished goods. Study facility design, perform time studies to assess personnel requirements, and perform cost analysis based on activity levels. Create bill of materials (BOMs) and routing of products in Microsoft Dynamics.

- ► Collaborated with team of financial consultants provide analysis, reporting tools, and engineering support for cost change initiative project. Improved accuracy of times for increased fidelity cost models and production control planning for more than 200 product lines in four months.
- ► Worked closely with technical team to develop and implement Microsoft based mobile app with PowerApps

ALPLA Group
Process Engineer
August 2014 - October 2017 (3 years 3 months)
Greater Atlanta Area

Travelled domestically and internationally to collaborate with teams to develop innovative, new ideas that improved and enhanced product development of plastic injection and extrusion molded consumer good packaging to everchanging marketplace. Led and developed technical, hands-on experiments

with production machinery to troubleshoot electrical, hydraulic, pneumatic, PLC, HMI systems. Ensured generation of valid, defensible, and supportable engineering conclusions during data collection stage.

- ► Developed 3D printed quality tool that increased testing standardization across all production sites and reduced false negative quality control data occurrences by 33%.
- ► Served as member of product development team to manage and complete multi-million dollar projects across multi-site facilities to produce multiple product lines. Efforts resulted in launch of 100+ new products from development into production.

Flambeau, Inc.
Project Engineer
2012 - 2014 (3 years)

Greater Atlanta Area

Liaised between clients and internal departments to ensure customer expectations were understood and met about cost, quality, delivery, and service. Communicated with clients to identify and resolve quality complaints. Led new production startups and maintained ongoing production. Developed quality control plans, operator instructions, and technical setup documentation.

- ► Successfully launched and supported 6 GM product lines into production at continued manufacturing support and completed 40+ product line transfer during plant shut down and absorption
- ► Completed GP-12 quarantine, while automotive quality standards were maintained.

General Dynamics Land Systems Manufacturing Quality Engineer 2012 - 2012 (1 year) Anniston, Alabama Area

Contractor

## Education

Mercer University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Industrial Engineering · (2011)